Guide to the Horace Walpole Collection
The Lewis Walpole Library
- Horace Walpole's Manuscripts, Series II
  - [List of pamphlets written by Sir Robert Walpole]., No date; [1] leaf; 23 cm. (Box 40, Folder 33)
    The ms. is a rough draft of the list that appeared in A Catalogue of the royal and noble authors of England, 1758.
  - [Lists of portraits]., No date; 5 items; 23 cm or smaller. (Box 40, Folder 34)
    The mss. are probably lists of portraits that Horace Walpole wanted to buy. Some names are crossed through, probably as he acquired them.
  - [List of Thomas Gray's and Lord Hervey's works]., No date; [2] p.; 19 cm. (Box 40, Folder 35)
    Horace Walpole included Lord Hervey's works in A Catalogue of the royal and noble authors, 1758, v. 2, p. 137-43.
  - L[ord] Orford's real quarters., No date; [1] scrap; 10 x 9 cm. (Box 40, Folder 36)
    On the verso Horace Walpole refers to Blomefield's Norfolk and the Huntingdon family connection.
  - [Memoranda] 1771-1785, Advice to my successors at Strawberry Hill. *, Between 1771 and 1785; 4 items; 24 cm or smaller. (Box 40, Folder 37)
    Horace Walpole discusses his neighbors and his property at Strawberry Hill in four memoranda: 1771 Jun. 3, 1781 Jul. 1, 1784 Feb. 28, 1785 Jul.
    Accompanied by a cover for the mss. inscribed by Mary Berry.
  - [Memorandum] 1790 Mar 21, Directions for my executors ... *, Circa 1797; 1 leaf, folded; 41 cm. (Box 40, Folder 38)
    Accompanied by a cover with ms. title: For my executors ...
    Also includes the Memorandum, 1790 Mar. 21, endorsed 1796 Aug. 19, on boxes A and B which begins: In my library ...
    Ms. begins: I would have my ancient copy ...
    Transcript in Mary Berry's[?] hand.
    Cf. Yale Edition, v. 17, p. xlii; v. 36, p. 310-16.
    Cf. Lord Holland's edition of the Memoirs, 1847, p. v-vi.
  - [Memorandum] 1790 Mar 21, [on boxes A and B]. *, 1796 Aug 19; 1 leaf; 14 x 21 cm. (Box 40, Folder 39)
    Identified by Horace Walpole as N[umbe]r 3.
    Endorsed by Mary Berry: Directions Box A & B, 1796.
    Ms. begins: In my library at Strawberry Hill are two wainscot chests ...
    Cf. Yale Edition, v. 36, p. 274, p. 310-16.
  - [Memorandum] 1790 Mar 21, [on boxes A and B]., 1796 Aug 19; [2] leaves; 32 cm. (Box 40, Folder 40)
    Written in a clerk's hand.
    Ms. begins: In my library at Strwaberry Hill ...
    Also includes the Memorandum 1794 Jun. 26, on box A which begins: In the round library of books of prints ...
    Endorsed in an unknown hand with ms. title: Directions not to be opened till after my will.
  - [Memorandum] 1794 Jun 26, [on box A]. *, 1 leaf; 20 cm. (Box 40, Folder 41)
    Ms. begins: In the round library of books of prints ...
    Annotated in pencil: None of the papers to be ever printed.
    Identified by Horace Walpole as N[umbe]r 2.
    Endorsed by Mary Berry: 1794 Box A.
  - Narrative of the Proceedings on the intended marriage between Lord Orford and Miss Nicholl: in a letter addressed to Mrs. Harris, my Lord's grandmother: a draft in Horace Walpole's hand, 1751 August 7 (Box 44)
    Yale edition, v. 14, p. [193]-214.
    [20] p.; 22.5 cm.
  - Narrative of the Proceedings on the intended marriage between Lord Orford and Miss Nicholl: in a letter addressed to Mrs. Harris, my Lord's grandmother, [1751 June]; [16] p.; 32 cm. (Box 44)
    Yale Edition, v. 14, p. [193]-214.
  - Nature will prevail: a moral entertainment in one act., 1773 Mar 1-2; [10] p. on [8] leaves; 23 cm. (Box 40, Folder 42)
    The original title, The contrast a comedy in two acts, is crossed out by Horace Walpole. The cover title is in Thomas Kirgate's hand. Includes a pencil sketch by Horace Walpole[?].
    Printed in 1773 or 1774 as part of Horace Walpole's Works, 1770, ii[289]-304; reprinted in Works, 1798, ii[289]-304.
  - [Notes for letters and other writings, lists, and aphorisms]., No date; 4 items (3 sheets and 1 card); 32 cm or smaller. (Box 40, Folder 43)
    One manuscript begins: The world can't be made by chance ...
    Another manuscript begins: Mr. Fox was in the room with Sir R.W. when he first heard the Q[ueen] was dying.
  - [Notes] from Weaver's Funeral monuments., No date; [1] leaf; 20 cm. (Box 40, Folder 44)
    Horace Walpole probably owned the first edition of John Weever's Ancient funerall monuments, 1631 (Hazen 643). His notes refer to men and women of Norfolk. The Robsarts and Fitzosberts were his ancestors.
  - [Notes of an interview with the Prince of Wales]. *, 1748 Mar 2 (Box 40, Folder 45)
    Listed with unpublished mss. in Allen Hazen's Bibliography of Horace Walpole, 1948, p. 177.
  - [Notes on a playing card]., [1749?]; [1] card (6 of spades), split; 10 x 7 cm. (Box 40, Folder 46)
    Includes: Horace Walpole's notes for his Commonplace Book on Sir Robert Brown and "You must first be set against" (Hazen 2616 I, p. 70, 73); notes for Horace Walpole's letter to Montagu, 26 Aug. 1749; an "Epitaph on Pope"; and an "Emendation (of Hamlet)."
  - [Notes on Camden's Britannia]., No date; [1] leaf; 32 cm. (Box 40, Folder 47)
  - [Notes on Dugdale's Warwickshire]. *, No date; [1] card; 10 x 7 cm. (Box 40, Folder 48)
  - [Notes on Elibank's A letter to the Honourable Sir David Dalrymple ...]., No date; [1] scrap, torn; 11 x 23 cm. (Box 40, Folder 49)
    Includes a poem in Horace Walpole's hand about David Rizzio and Mary Queen of Scots.
    Cf. Yale Edition, v. 16, p. 292n.
  - [Notes on Marvell's Growth of Popery]., No date; [2] p.; 23 cm. (Box 40, Folder 50)
  - [Notes on Montesquieu's Oeuvres]., No date; [1] scrap; 6 x 13 cm. (Box 40, Folder 51)
    Cf. A Catalogue of Horace Walpole's Library, no. 1621: Horace Walpole copied several passages from Montesquieu, presumably from this edition.
  - [Notes on Nicolson's The English historical library]., No date; [2] p. on [1] leaf, folded; 23 cm. (Box 40, Folder 52)
    Ms. title: Historical library.
    On the back cover is a pencil drawing of a man by Horace Walpole[?], 23 x 19 cm, corner torn.
  - [Notes on Walpole's quarrel with Mason]., No date; [1] scrap; 11 x 16 cm. (Box 40, Folder 53)
    Horace Walpole probably planned to expand these notes into a full account.
    Yale Edition, Appendix 1, v. 29, p. 352.
  - [Notes on Weever's Monuments, Lord Shaftesbury's speeches, and A brief history of the succession]., No date; [4] p.; 32 cm. (Box 40, Folder 54)
    Includes pencil drawings of unidentified women by Horace Walpole[?].
  - Notes to Mr. W[illiam] Mason's later poems., 1779; 21 p.; 23 cm or smaller. (Box 40, Folder 55)
    Also includes: An epistle to Sir William Chambers Knight / by John Chute, 1775. 4 p.
    Published in: Satirical poems published anonymously by William Mason, with notes by Horace Walpole / ed. Paget Toynbee, Oxford, 1926, from another version of the ms. as Harvard.
  - Old England: [contribution in] no. 158. *, 1747 May 16; [7, 1 blank] p.; 23 cm. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    Scene 1 of a play: The sea coast after a storm. Enter the Superior of a college.
    Published under title: Terrae filius, or, Harlequin candidate: a farce.
    Transcribed by Horace Walpole in his commonplace book of political papers, 1747-53, p. 9-13.
  - Old England: [contribution in] no. 162. *, 1747 Jun 13; [8] p.; 23 cm. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    Ms. title: Letter from a West Saxon to his friend in the country.
    Transcribed by Horace Walpole in his commonplace book of political papers, 1747-53, p. 13-18.
  - Old England: [contribution in] no. 164. *, 1747 Jun 20; [4] p. only; 23 cm. (Box 41, Folder 3)
    Ms. title: The alarm occasion'd by the intended dissolution of the Parliament.
  - Old England: [contribution in] no. 166. *, 1747 Jul 4; [8] p.; 23 cm. (Box 41, Folder 4)
    Published under pseudonym: Argus Centoculi, Inspector General of Great Britain.
    Ms. begins: The people of England ...
    Transcribed by Horace Walpole in his commonplace book of political papers, 1747-53, p. 23-26.
  - Old England: [contribution in] no. 182. *, 1747 Oct 24; [7, i blank] p.; 24 cm. (Box 41, Folder 5)
    Ms. begins: I have observed ...
    Transcribed by Horace Walpole in his commonplace book of political papers, 1747-53, p. 36-39.
  - Old England: [contribution in] no. 188. *, 1747 Dec 5; [4] p. only; 23. (Box 41, Folder 6)
    Published under pseudonym: Argus Cenoculi ...
    Ms. begins: As the constitution of Sweden ...
    First half of a dissertation on parliamentary affairs in Sweden and England; the complete dissertation is transcribed by Horace Walpole in his commonplace book of political papers, 1747-53, p. 40-43.
  - [On virtue]., No date; [1] scrap; 16 x 10 cm. (Box 41, Folder 7)
    Manuscript begins: My hands are tied up ...
  - [Persian letter], 1743 (Box 41, Folder 7a (object room))
    See note in Yale Edition, v. 18, p. 167, n. 6.
  - Portrait of Lord Mansfield. *, No date; [2] p. and [1] scrap; 20 cm or smaller. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Postscript to my Historic doubts. *, 1793 Feb; [2] p. on [2] leaves; 23 cm. (Box 41, Folder 9)
    Transcript in Thomas Kirgate's hand of the original ms. tipped in Horace Walpole's Historic doubts (Hazen 3909).
    Published in Horace Walpole's Works, 1798, v.2, p. *251-52.
  - Public Advertiser: [contributions in]. *, 1767 Aug 28 and Sep 2; [8] p.; 23 cm. (Box 41, Folder 10)
    Letters signed: Toby and A Constant Correspondent.
    Both mss. are on political abuse in newspapers.
    Ms. titles: For the Public Advertiser and To Mr. Woodfall.
    Yale Edition, Appendix 4, v. 42, p. 498-506.
  - [Political notes. 1714]., No date; [2] p. on one sheet; 16 cm. (Box 41, Folder 11)
    Notes on the accession of George I; Nicholas Rowe's Jane Shore; Sir Richard Steel; Bishop of Rochester; a speech by Sir Robert Walpole; the Duke of Argyll; Johann Bothmar; Lord Bolingbroke.
  - [Political notes. 1744-1745]. *, [2] p. on one sheet; 33 cm. (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - [Political notes. 1745 Jan 23]., 2 sides of a playing card; 9.5 x 6.25 cm. (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - [Political notes. 1745 Feb 18]. *, [4] p. on one folded sheet, a fragment; 15 cm. (Box 41, Folder 14)
    See Yale Edition, v. 19, p. 17, note 5.
  - [Political notes. 1745 Oct 23]. *, [2] p. on one sheet; 16 cm. (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - [Political notes. 1745 Nov 1]. *, 4 p. on one folded sheet; 20 cm. (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - [Political notes. 1745 Dec 19]. *, [2] p. on one folded sheet; 19 cm. (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - [Political notes. 1751-1771]. *, [1] p.; 23 cm. (Box 41, Folder 18)
    Horace Walpole's brief list of his manuscripts for memoirs of Geo. II and III.
  - [Political notes. 1751-1760]: Index of the 100 characters [for Memoirs of George II]., [2] p. on one sheet; 31 cm. (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - [Political notes. 1761 Nov 13]: Address on the King's speech., 7 p. on two folded sheets; 23 cm. (Box 41, Folder 20)
    Memoirs of the reign of King George III, 1894, v. 1, p. 71-77.
    See also: Diary of a journey to England, 1761-1762, by Kielmansegge, p. 160-66.
  - [Political notes. 1767 Jul 15]. *, 2 ms., each one on a folded sheet; 20 cm. (Box 41, Folder 21)
    Draft of a letter in Horace Walpole's hand. Also, a draft of a letter (in Lord Hertford's hand) for the Duke of Grafton to send to Lord Rockingham, with corrections by Horace Walpole.
    Memoirs of the reign of King George III, 1894, v. 3, p. 51-53.
    See also: Brooke, John. The Chatham administration, 1766-1768, 1956, p. 190-96.
    See also: Yale Edition, v. 22, p. 539.
  - [Political notes. 1769]: The history of Madame du Barry, mistress of Louis quinze., [10] p. on three folded sheets; 23 cm. (Box 41, Folder 22)
    Memoirs of the reign of King George III, 1894, v. 4, p. 4-20.
  - [Political notes. 1770]: [Character of Lord North]., [1] p.; 23.25 cm. (Box 41, Folder 23)
    Memoirs of the reign of King George III, 1894, v. 4, p. 52-54.
  - [Political notes. 1771]. *, 1 scrap. (Box 41, Folder 24)
    Count Casimir Pulawski, 1748-1779, and the assassination plot.
    Cf. Yale Edition, v. 23, p. 359, note 10.
  - [Political notes. 1774 May and Sep 7]. *, [2] p. on one fragment; 20 x 18.5 cm. (Box 41, Folder 25)
    Provision for Duchess of Gloucester and her children; includes list of miscellaneous headings for Sept. 1774.
    Cf. Last journals, ed. by Steuart, 1910, v.1, p. 369-70 (Aug. 1774).
  - [Political notes. 1775-1785]. *, 3 scraps. (Box 41, Folder 26)
    Lists of names.
  - [Political notes. 1775]. *, 2 sides of a card; 9.25 x 6.25 cm. (Box 41, Folder 27)
    Notes for letters to Lady Ossory, 19 and 24 Jan. 1775; notes for Last journals, Dec. 1775.
    "K. thought arm was off" [Duke of Gloucester's]. Cf. Last journals, 1910, v.1, p. 504-6 (Dec. 1775).
  - [Political notes. 1775]. *, 2 sides of a card; 9.5 x 6.5 cm. (Box 41, Folder 28)
    Memoranda for memoirs.
    "Nuttall died £1900 in K's debt." Cf. Last journals, 1910, v.1, p. 469 (July 1775).
    Illustration in W.S. Lewis's Mellon Lectures, 1960, p. 87.
  - [Political notes. 1775 Aug, Sep, Oct]., [2] p. on one sheet; 19 x 12 cm. (Box 41, Folder 29)
    Cf. Horace Walpole's Last journals, 1910, edited by Steuart.
  - [Political notes. 1776 Feb 5]. *, 1 fragment; 9 x 11 cm. (Box 41, Folder 30)
    Duke of Gloucester to Rome.
    Cf. Horace Walpole's Last journals, edited by Steuart, v.1, p. 525.
  - [Political notes. 1777 Sep 20]: New York, Sept. 20, 1777. *, [1] p.; 20 cm. (Box 41, Folder 31)
    "... on 11th ... Washington retreated to Germantown ..."
  - [Political notes. 1777 Nov]. *, [2] p. on one sheet; 20 x 16 cm. (Box 41, Folder 32)
    Application of Benjamin Franklin and Silas Deane for exchange of prisoners.
    Last Journals of Horace Walpole, 1910, v.2, p. 77 (Nov. 1777).
  - [Political notes. 1778?]: A summary review of the loss of America ... *, 1 fragment; 21 cm. (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - [Political notes. 1780?]. *, 2 sides of a card; 9.25 x 6.25 cm. (Box 41, Folder 34)
    Notes on the Duke of Gloucester's reconciliation with the King?
    Cf. The Last Journals of Horace Walpole, 1910, edited by Steuart, v.2, p. 313-19.
  - [Political notes. 1780 Sep]., 1 fragment; 6 x 4.5 cm. (Box 41, Folder 35)
    Cf. Last Journals of Horace Walpole, 1910, edited by Steuart, v.2, p. 329-30 (Sept. 1780).
  - [Political notes. 1781 Dec]., 1 side of a card; 9.25 x 6.25 cm. (Box 41, Folder 36)
    Memoranda (some crossed out) for memoirs.
    The first entry, "17. Hyder Alli. Sir E. Coote," refers to Last Journals of Horace Walpole, 1910, edited by Steuart, v.2, p. 390 (17 Dec. 1781).
  - [Political notes. 1782-1784]: Journal of weather at [Richmond] house. * (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - [Political notes. 1782]. *, 2 sides of one fragment; 16 cm. (Box 41, Folder 38)
    Dated by W.S. Lewis's note on typescript: "ca. Feb. 1782."
  - [Political notes. 1782]: [List of honours and promotions in Rockingham's ministry]., [4] p. on one folded sheet; 31 cm. (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - [Political notes. 1782]., 1 fragment; 19.5 x 5 cm. (Box 41, Folder 40)
    Cf. letter from Horace Walpole to Lady Ossory, 22 Jun. 1782, regarding the Bishop of Peterborough. Yale Edition, v. 33, p. 338.
  - [Political notes. 1782]. *, [1] p.; 16.25 cm. (Box 41, Folder 41)
  - [Political notes. 1782 Jan-Mar]. *, [4] p. on one folded sheet; 16 cm. (Box 41, Folder 42)
    A list of memoranda for The Last Journals, and notes on symptoms of gout.
    Cf. The Last Journals ..., ed. by Steuart, 1910, v.2, p. 395-423.
  - [Political notes. 1782 July 5-10]. *, 2 fragments; 16 x 10 cm and 4 x 20 cm. (Box 41, Folder 43)
    Cf. The Last Journals ..., ed. by Steuart, 1910, v.2, p. 445-460.
    Cf. letter from Horace Walpole to Horace Mann, 7 July 1782. Yale Edition, v. 25, p. 292-95.
  - [Political notes. 1783]. *, [4] p. on two fragments; 16 x 10 cm and 10.5 x 5 cm. (Box 41, Folder 44)
    Cf. The Last Journals ..., ed. by Steuart, 1910, v.2, p. 448n.
  - [Political notes. 1783 April]. *, [3] p. on one sheet and one fragment; 23 x 19 cm and 18.5 x 12 cm. (Box 41, Folder 45)
    Cf. letter from Horace Walpole to Horace Mann, 3 April 1783.
  - [Political notes. 1783 Sep?]. *, 1 fragment, torn; 17.5 x 17.5 cm. (Box 41, Folder 46)
  - [Political notes. Ca. 1784]. *, 1 fragment; 6 x 16 cm. (Box 41, Folder 47)
    Notes, including anecdote on General Imhoff "selling" his wife to Warren Hastings.
    Cf. Yale Edition, v. 11, p. 295, note 10.
    Dated by W.S. Lewis with reference to "Duke of Dorset to France ..."
    In Horace Walpole's manuscript for the Memoirs 1783-1791, sub 13 Feb. 1787, he refers to "the scandal" concerning Mrs. Hastings.
  - [Political notes. 1784]: Games played at on Twelfth Night by new ministers, 1784. *, 1 fragment; 11.5 x 12 cm. (Box 41, Folder 48)
  - [Political notes. 1784 Jan]: A compleat answer to all associations for novel and fantastic modes of representation., [1] p.; 23 cm. (Box 41, Folder 49)
  - [Political notes. 1784 Mar-1785]. *, [5] p. on two folded sheets; 19 x 11.5 cm. (Box 41, Folder 50)
  - [Political notes. Ca. 1786]: Intelligence extraordinary. *, [2] p. and 1 fragment; 22.5 x 18 cm and 9 x 15 cm. (Box 41, Folder 51)
    Typescript dated "c1786" by W.S. Lewis.
    Notes on Charles Jenkinson, Earl of Liverpool. Includes anecdote on Baron Imhoff, his wife, and Warren Hastings.
  - [Political notes. Ca. 1788]. *, 1 fragment; 11.5 x 9.5 cm. (Box 41, Folder 52)
    Dated by mention of publication of Memoires by Madame de la Motte. Cf. Yale Edition, v. 11, p. 4-5n.
  - [Political notes. 1788 Dec 4]., [10] p. on three folded sheets; 24 cm. (Box 41, Folder 53)
    Written in an unidentified hand.
    An account of this debate was written by Horace Walpole. See Last Journals ..., ed. by Steuart, 1910, v.2, p. 219. See also Yale Edition, v. 24, p. 426, n. 6 and p. 429, n. 3.
  - [Political notes. 1788 Dec 12]. *, [1] p. on half sheet; 11 x 18 cm. (Box 41, Folder 54)
    Notes on the appointment of a Regent.
  - [Political notes. Ca. 1789]., One side of a card; 9 x 6.25 cm. (Box 41, Folder 55)
    Dated by Horace Walpole's note: "26. Fox to Bath." Cf. Yale Edition, v. 34, p. 37, n. 21.
  - [Political notes. 1789 Jan 15]: The London Chronicle, Jan. 15, 1789. *, 1 fragment; 9.5 x 15.5 cm. (Box 41, Folder 56)
    Horace Walpole's draft of a notice regarding "various rumours on the subject of his Maj. supposed personal estate; his last will ..."
  - Quante anime sono ..., No date; 1 card; 6 x 9 cm. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    Horace Walpole's notes in Italian are written on the back of a six of clubs.
  - [Quotations from Dryden, Addison, and Ovid]., No date; [2] p.; 20 cm. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - [Quotations from Livy, Plato, Hobbes, and Bacon]., No date; [3] p. on [2] leaves; 20 cm. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - [Reply to James Barry]., Circa 1755; [2] p.; 20 cm. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    Yale Edition, v. 34, Appendix 4.
  - Rules for obtaining a ticket to visit Strawberry Hill., [Between 1791 and 1797] (Box 42, Folder 4a)
  - Sayings of Mr. Winnington. *, No date; [4] p.; 23 cm. (Box 42, Folder 5)
    Includes amusing anecdotes about Mrs. Trip, Lady Burlington, Lady Townshend, Mr. Fox, Lord Vane, Lord Fielding, Sir Butler Charnock, Mrs. Hamilton, Bishop of Rochester, Sir Charles Williams, Lord Lincoln, Lady Sandys, and Alexander Pope.
  - [Scheme for the encouragement of historic painting in England]. *, 1785 Feb 9; [2] p.; 23 cm. (Box 42, Folder 6)
    Ms. begins: It is a common complaint ...
    Transcript in the hand of Thomas Kirgate; the same ms. in Horace Walpole's hand is in the Pierpont Morgan Library.
  - She was the eldest daughter to Theophilus Howard ..., No date; [1] scrap; 4 x 22 cm. (Box 42, Folder 7)
    Annotation cut from the bottom of a portrait of Catherine Howard bought at the Strawberry Hill sale.
    Horace Walpole supplied James Granger with a similar note for his Biographical history of England, v.1, pt.2, p. 552 (Hazen 541).
  - [Signature]., No Date; [1] scrap, vellum; 4 x 12 cm. (Box 42, Folder 8)
    Horace Walpole's signature was cut from a document.
  - [Sir Robert Walpole's last words]., [1745 Mar 25]; [1] leaf; 23 cm. (Box 42, Folder 9)
    First line: D[ea]r Horace, this lixivium has blown me up.
    Yale Edition, v. 26, Appendix 4, p. [12].
  - S[i]r Will[iam] Thorpe, Chief Justice in the time of Edw[ard] 3 ..., 1743; [1] scrap; 12 x 19 cm. (Box 42, Folder 10)
    The ms. also includes Horace Walpole's notes on Parliament during the reign of Richard II, the cost of licenses to preach and practice medicine, and collegiate and cathedral revenues. On the verso is Horace Walpole's note on the Spanish war, Sept. 1743.
  - S[i]r William Waad ... *, Circa 1762; [1] leaf; ill., port.; 32 cm. (Box 42, Folder 11)
    Includes an engraving of Sir William Waad by Thomas Jenner.
    Horace Walpole published this description of Sir William Waad in a footnote to A Catalogue of engravers, 1763, p. 18.
  - Sketch of a history written in a method entirely new., Circa 1782; 12 leaves; 32 cm. (Box 42, Folder 12)
    Pseudonym following title: John Short, gent.
    A fragmentary first draft of this satire was printed by Dr. Doran in The last journals of Horace Walpole, for July 1782, with alternate title: Sketch of a new method of writing history.
  - [Speech before the House of Commons on the Buckinghamshire Assizes Bill]. *, [1748 Apr 6]; [4] p.; 31 cm. (Box 42, Folder 13)
    Horace Walpole's speech was never delivered.
    Accompanied by an engraving of Horace Walpole, printed in London by Henry Colburn, 1851, and a note by John Wilson Croker.
  - [Speech before the House of Commons on the retention of Hanoverian troops]. *, [1744 Jan 18]; 6 p.; 32 cm or smaller. (Box 42, Folder 14)
    Ms. begins: Mr. Fane, if the dignity of any assembly can awe ...
    Cf. Yale Edition, v. 19, p. 241n.
  - The spirit of the present reign detailed in a series of plain and undeniable facts for the use of the nation., 1760-1763; 5 p. on [3] folded leaves; 32 cm. (Box 42, Folder 15)
    Notes incorporated into the Memoirs of the reign of King George the Third.
    Accompanied by a scrap and another version labeled: Summary from accession to 1763 meant to begin a pamphlet, p. 3-4 on [1] leaf, folded.
  - This copy has some few additions ..., 1788; [1] scrap; 18 x 12 cm. (Box 42, Folder 16)
    Horace Walpole probably wrote this note on the original wrapper of Mary Berry's copy of the Description. Endorsed by Mary Berry[?].
    Accompanied by an article on the Strawberry Hill sale from the Times, 1842 Mar. 18, and an engraving of Horace Walpole by Dean after Zincke, published by Richard Bentley, 1857.
    Hazen, Allen T. A Bibliography of the Strawberry Hill Press, p. 125.
    Cf. Sotheby Catalogue, 6 Jul. 1931, lot 155.
  - Thoughts on comedy., 1775-1776; 6 leaves; 32 cm. (Box 42, Folder 17)
    Transcript in Thomas Kirgate's hand.
    Endorsed by Mary Berry.
    Published in Horace Walpole's Works, 1798, v.2, p. 315-22.
  - View of farm yard & printing house at Strawberry Hill., No date; [1] leaf; 17 x 20 cm. (Box 42, Folder 18)
    Includes a sketch by Horace Walpole in pen-and-ink of the barn, tee house, and printing house at Strawberry Hill.
    Annotated by Thomas Kirgate: Sketch by Mr. Walpole (when his hands were wrapt in bootikins in a fit of the gout) for a print, before that by Edwards was made.
  - These papers were Mr. George Vertue's, the engraver, & relate to his being employed by Frederick, Prince of Wales, whose handwriting appears among them., Circa 1758; [1] scrap; 10 x 19 cm. (Box 42, Folder 19)
    Walpole bought 40 volumes of Vertue's notes on 22 Aug. 1758. This ms. note was probably written on the cover of one of the notebooks.
    The ms. was removed from one of the extra-illustrated volumes of Horace Walpole by Austin Dobson now in the Lewis Walpole Library.
  - [Verse]: Didicit prius extimuitque magistrum. *, Circa 1730; 1 item ([4] p.); 19 cm. (Box 42, Folder 20)
    Latin verses written by Horace Walpole probably while a student at Eton.